Freedom is my nature.
The Rising Hawk is a action, history, drama film directed by Akhtem Seitablaiev.
During the 13th century, a small village fights for freedom in the frontier
landscape of the Carpathian Mountains against Mongolian invaders.
Maksym, played by Alex MacNicoll.
Myroslava, played by Poppy Drayton.
Ivan, played by Rocky Myers.
Rosana, played by Alina Kovalenko.
Zakhar Berkut, played by Robert Patrick.
Tuhar Vovk, played by Tommy Flanagan.
The Rising Hawk: Battle for the Carpathians (Ukrainian: «Захар Беркут», romanized: Zahar Berkut, also called Fall of a Kingdom in the United
Kingdom) is a 2019 Ukrainian-American historical action film directed by John Wynn and co-directed by Akhtem Seitablayev.
It is based on the historical fiction novella Zakhar Berkut by Ukrainian writer and poet Ivan
Franko, taking place in the Carpathians during the 13th-century Mongol invasions.
The film premiered on October 10, 2019.
The word berkut is the name for golden eagle, a type of eagle.
The film explores themes of mongol, 13th century, carpathians.
The tone is emotional.